呜汪！你再也不能这样叫了
Bow wow! You can't bark like that anymore.
因为…这个星球上的一切都被烧尽
Because...everything on this planet is burnt,
融化 压碎了…
melted, crushed...
人类已经死亡 腐烂
Humans are dead, rotten,
狗狗们在他们的身上啃啊啃
and the doggie is nom, nom, nom, noming on them like it's a feast.
话说 食物可是很重要的！
I mean, isn't food important, after all?
因为“人如其食”所以要小心啊
Yes, you must be very careful because you are what you eat.
吃了不该吃的东西的话
So when someone eats something they shouldn't eat,
会怎样呢？
what happens then?
会怎样呢?!
What happens then?!
他们的身体会变得与之前不同
Well, that person becomes something they are not,
这就是说…
and that means...
是的 这意味着…
Yes, that means...
他们来了
Oh, here there are.
他们好可爱喔
They're so cute, huh?
他们在找什么？
Are they searching for something?
他们好像嗅到了什么
Oh, and it appears they smell something.
这边的也很可爱！
Ooh, these guys are adorable, too!
拉近镜头 摄影师！
Zoom in, Mr. Cameraman!
看不出他们的表情
I can't read the expressions on their faces,
所以不知道他们心情如何
so I'm not sure how they feel.
但这正是他们的可爱之处！
But that's what's so gosh-darn cute about them!
啊！好棒！
Oh! Fantastic!
之前还那样的温文尔雅
Unlike their delightfully civilized entrance,
现在变得好粗暴
that was quite savage!
真棒！谢谢你 世界！
(意语)Bravissimo! (日语)Arigato,world!
今天又被吞食掉了
I am devoured once again today,
被完全彻底地撕开了
completely and neatly split open.
然后我终于想起
And then I finally remember.
我从不曾拥有什么
I had nothing forever and ever.
还有我们在地球上
And we are on planet Earth...
还有我们在地球上…
And we are on planet Earth and...
我在说什么？
What was I saying?
女仆咖啡厅   雲雀
停！
No!
“拌拌匀咖喱饭”是要在客人的面前拌匀的
Mixy-Mixy Curry Rice needs to be mixed in front of the customer!
所以才叫“拌拌匀”的
It's Mixy-Mixy for a reason,
所以不要在上桌前就拌匀 明白了吗？！
so don't mix it before you take it to the table, all right?!
酷美 亲爱的 早上好
Oh, hello, Hidomi, dear. Good morning.
酷美 小心那个女人 骑着 Ve——
Hidomi, beware of the woman on the Vesp--
下一个 帕菲“苦中带甜不求回报的爱”
Next, Bittersweet Unrequited Love Parfait.
路上小心！
Have a nice day, dear!
糟透了
A nightmare.
别忘了那个女人 骑着 Ve——
Don't forget, the woman on the Vesp--
F  L  C  L
Freebie  Honey
本字幕由 SweetSub 制作　仅做交流学习之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
嘿 哟！你们的老师 晴子
Hey, yo! I'm your teacher, Miss Haruko!
你们所在的世界
The world you live in
正在不负责任地溢出
is now overflowing irresponsibly.
不管你看向哪里
No matter which direction you look,
到处都有人用自私的妄想
you'll see the world is full of those who defile others
污染其他人和周围的环境
and their surroundings with selfish delusions.
我真心地相信
And I truly believe that this is solely
这全都是这世上大人们的错
the fault of the adults of this world,
与此同时 很不幸地
and when I say that, I unfortunately,
我也是他们中的一员
include myself among them.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我的想法和以前不同了
I cannot think like I used to.
我不能继续下去
I can no longer continue.
噗噼噼
Pupipi.
即使我努力去为这个星球考虑
Even if I try to think what's best for this planet,
我只会想到以前不曾注意的鼹鼠
I think about the mole that I haven't noticed before,
或是它身上的毛发
or the hair that grows out of it.
没办法 我总是想到这些东西
I can't help but think about these things.
世界 宇宙
World. Universe.
实话说 我不在乎
To be honest, I don't care.
因为这不是我的错
Because it's actually not my fault.
噗噗噗
Puppuppu.
噗噼噗
Puppippu.
乖 好孩子们
There, there. You're good kids. Good talk.
说了那么多 饿死了 剩下的时间大家自习
Well, I'm hungry, so use the rest of class for self-study.
差点忘了说 好消息
Before I forget, I have good news.
年鉴终于做好了
The yearbook has finally been completed.
来看看吧
So check it out!
年鉴？
Yearbook?
看 这是运动会的！
Oh, hey, that was from Sports Day!
我记得很清楚！
I totally remember that!
那次真是厉害
Yeah, it was epic.
球技大会
晴子老师为了让对方出局
Miss Haruko's wicked pitch
故意投出的坏球 真够恶意
when she gets them to pop it for an easy out.
最后一轮晴子老师满垒下的逆转封杀时
Miss Haruko's last round full base comeback line
胜利!!
击中投手的那个平飞球！
drive to the pitcher! -Whoa!
太牛逼了！
-Yeah! -Legendary.
美好的记忆
Good times.
放学后召唤UFO！！
放学后向 UFO 发出信号
We sent a signal to a UFO after school,
邀请灵能力者来文化祭
and we invited that psychic to our Cultural Festival.
还有 在掰弯勺子大赛中
Plus, during the spoon bending competition,
晴子老师掰弯了对手的手指获得了胜利
Miss Haruko bent her opponent's fingers and won!
在庆祝派对上我们用学校楼顶搞了一场篝火
Hmm. And we used the school building to make a bonfire at the after party.
♪ 烧啊 烧啊 烧啊 烧啊... ♪
♪ Burn, burn, burn, burn, burn, burn, burn, burn... ♪
真是美好的记忆啊
These sure are some great memories.
我们是最好的班级
Man, we had the best class ever.
我们真的很幸运
Yeah. We sure were lucky, weren't we?
♪ 灰烬飞舞眼前 ♪
♪ See the embers as they fly by ♪
♪ 火光照亮夜空
♪ Burn into the night sky
雲雀弄…嘿？
Hibaji...Hey?
帮我转交个东西吧？
Can you deliver this for me?
给井出亲 他今天没来学校
For Ide-chi. He was absent.
为什么找我？
Why do you want me to do it?
我也不知道 为什么呢？
I don't know. Why, indeed?
因为你们关系不错？
Because you two are close?
对吧？
Am I right?
-我说错了吗？-不晓得
-Well, are you? -I don't know.
嗯？
Hmm?
OK！谢啦！
Okay! Thank you!
妈妈 这公园好无聊
Mommy, this park is boring!
确实有点旧 需要改造了
Well, it is a bit old. It needs to be updated.
扫地机器人！
Neato!
看起来像从外太空来的！
Looks like it's from outerspace!
哇！好酷！
Whoa! Cool!
我还要工作多久？！
How much longer do I need to work?!
嘿 公主小姐
Hey, princess!
你在这个地方做什么？
Whatever you doing in these parts?
-你是店里的客人 -你看这样如何？
-Oh. You're the customer. What do you say?
要不要成为职业人士？
How would you like to become a pro, huh?
你会很厉害的 成为业内翘楚
You'll be great. A real phenomenon.
她才不会想要做职业人士！
She's not gonna wanna be a pro!
请您别缠着她 她不是——
Please leave her alone, sir. She isn't -- Mmm?
-你是个拉丁裔啊？-呃 是的
-You have Latin blood in you, don't ya? -Well, yeah.
那你呢？要不要做个职业人士？
How about you? Wanna be a pro?
你会很厉害的
You would be great.
成为业内翘楚的
A real phenomenon.
抱歉打断你 先生
Hate to break it to you, sir,
你才不会随随便便在大街上找到业界翘楚
but you're not just gonna find a phenomenon off the streets.
我们走
Let's go.
你的拳头不错
You have a fine fist.
我跟你说 你应该成为职业人士
I'm telling you, you should become a pro.
所以 到底是职业的什么？
Yeah, but a pro what?
那么 我们来想想
Uh, well, let's see.
你是来给井出带作业的吧？
You're dropping off Ide's worksheet, right?
嗯
Yeah.
像你这样的女孩子一个人在这里很不安全
This isn't really a great place for a girl to come by herself.
雲雀弄 你确定想看到井出真正的样子吗？
Hibajiri. Are you sure you wanna see the real Ide is like?
这是什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
好吧 反正你马上就要看到了
Well, like it or not, you're about to see for yourself.
就在这！
Here you go!
别停下！
Come on, keep it moving!
你们这些弱柴 就这点能耐吗！
You gotta give me more than that, you weaklings!
是的 长官
Sir, yes, sir!
你们以为桌上的食物是白给你们的吗？！
Who do you think is responsible for the food on your table?!
不要想偷懒 你们这些杂碎！
Now, put your backs into it, you pieces of shit!
那可不是初中生的身体
That's not the body of a middle-school kid.
那个肌肉线条雕刻完美的身体
That beautiful, sculpted body that is comparable,
完全不输于我！
yet superior to mine!
快点 动起来！
Hurry up and move it!
接着干活 没种的小子！
Get back to work, you dickless brat!
是的 长官！
Yes, sir!
他剃着板寸头 假装是班上的小丑
He pretends to be the class clown sporting a buzz cut
整天装傻
and acting all dumb at school,
其实他生活中吃饭都困难
but in reality, he's actually struggling to make ends meet.
但他从不会向我们展现他生活的另一面
But he wouldn't show that side of his life to any of us, though.
是的 长官
Sir, yes, sir!
那边的 跑起来
You there! Pick up your feet!
一二一
Hut! Hut! Hut!
来看看啊！这价格可优惠了！
Come, check it out! You can't beat these bargains!
井出制造厂
这是高性能的定制武器
These are high performance custom weapons,
由本天才手工制作
lovingly crafted by this genius, right here.
这是能发射一百个石子的自动式机枪
This one's an automatic machine gun that can fire 100 pebbles!
而且它只能用5毫米直径的石子
And it only takes pebbles that are exactly 5 millimeters!
功能多样
It's very versatile.
我知道你在想什么
Now, I know what you're thinking,
“哪里有这种尺寸的石子”
"But, sir, I cannot possibly find pebbles that size."
那么 我可有解决办法呢
Well then, do I have the item for you?
睁大眼睛看吧!
Feast your eyes!
这是超级奇怪强大的粉碎机
It's the super eccentric almighty pulverization machine,
能在几秒钟之内把岩石碾碎成 5 毫米直径的石子
crushing rocks into 5-millimeter pebbles in more seconds!
你说什么？不方便携带？
What's that, you say? You can't carry all of this?
对于需要帮忙搬运器材的人
Well, for those who need help lugging around their equipment,
我准备了这个！看！
I have this! I present to you,
绝赞的百发石子机枪和超级奇怪强大的粉碎机
the magnificent 100-shot pebble machine gun and super eccentric almighty pebble
专用手推板车！
pulverization machine dolly!
-这不就是个普通的板车 -嗯？
-Looks like a normal dolly to me. -Hmm?
好了 那么
All right, then.
你们谁想先来试试？
Now, which of you would like to try it first?
这位老哥 要来试试吗？
You wanna give it a go, tough guy?
やめろ！
Yamero!
他们为什么不住手？
Why won't they stop?
他们不知道“やめろ”的意思吗？
Don't they know what"yamero"means?
他用他们的语言说了 但是他们还是不听
He's speaking their language and they still won't listen.
我好心痛
Just breaks my heart.
你说这是什么？[哔]逗我吗？（日语）
なんだこりゃ～　バ〇？
没法杀人的机枪？别搞笑了
何の道殺せなねぇマシンガンなんで　笑わせんねぇ
这种废物拿来有什么用
いなねぇよ　こんなガラクタ
やめろ！不要 别这样 求你了
Yamero! No, no, no! S-Stop it! Stop it, please!
闭嘴！
黙れ！
还想要再揍你一顿吗？
もっと殴られたいのか
让你们失望了 抱歉
Sorry to disappoint.
你们不管怎么打我 都不会觉得疼
But no matter how many times you punch me, I feel no pain.
我的心已经冻结了
My heart is frozen.
别！别打了！
No! Please! No!
我错了！别打了！
Sorry! Stop!
我说错了话了！
I'm sorry for what I said before!
我错了！
I'm sorry.
真挫
ダサい
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我去 怎么了？
Whoa! What the hell?
森？雲雀弄？
Mori? Hibajiri?
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
喂，雲雀弄！醒醒！你怎么了？！
Hey, Hibajiri?! Wake up! Are you okay?!
为什么他桃花运那么好？
Why does he always get all the girls?
交 亲爱的！我做了一些炖蔬菜
Koh, dear! I made some stewed veggies for you.
天啊！天啊！
Oh, my goodness! Lordy, lordy!
你又带了一个女孩回家？！
You brought another girl home again?!
你这个坏小子
Oh, you nasty, nasty little boy.
年轻就是好
Oh, to be so young again.
要知道 想当年我也是个小——
You know, when I was young, I was also quite the little --
快出去！
Get out!
对不起 我没事的
Sorry. I'm okay.
好吧
Okay.
我忘了问你了 雲雀弄
Oh! I forgot to ask you, Hibajiri.
你是那种喜欢空间的人吗？
Are, uh, you the type of person who likes space?
我是说 外太空？
Like outerspace?
我们可以去看太空艺术展
We could go to see space art.
毕竟 人与人之间的关系就像星球之间一样
Ah! After all, relationships are like in the stars...
像 夜空中的星星一样
or like, stars in the night sky.
不不不不
Mmm. Oh! No, no, no!
我不是说我们俩在交往！
I don't mean we're in a relationship!
我们可以单纯去看展览而已！所以 挑一个…日子
We could just go! So, pick a...date.
不不 不是约会的意思
No, it wouldn't be a date!
-对不起 - 什么？
I'm sorry. Sorry?
不过谢谢约我
Thanks for asking.
那个...
I guess... Mm-hmm.
如果是井出的话 可以的哦
...if it were with you, Ide, I'd be fine with it.
交往什么的
To be in a relationship.
Cut！完美！
And cut! Perfect!
真是太完美了 井出亲！
That was just perfect, Ide-chi!
棒极了！可以去拿小金人了！
Bravo! Oscar-worthy!
你 你什么时候起在这里的？
Wh-- When did you get in here?
-晴子老师?! -大家稍事休息
-Miss Haruko?!  -Everyone, let's take five!
准备拍下一个场景！
Rolling on the next take!
最终场景
The final take.
雲雀… 雲雀…雲雀弄！
Hiba-Hiba-Hibajiri!
啊…温柔一点！
Aah, please don't be so rough!
别搞了行不行？
Will you cut it out?! Aah!
终于找到你了
I finally found you.
就不能让我好好上个厕所吗
Can't you just let me go to the bathroom in peace?
怎么回事？她是谁？小偷？
W-What's going on? Who is she anyway? A thief?
-不 我认识她 她是… - 你是谁哈？
-No, I know her. She's... -Who are you?
哈路哈·拉哈路 别装作不认识我
You can't pretend that you don't know me, Haruhara Haru.
我真后悔认识你
Rue the day I met you.
你尽管后悔 但逃避我无济于事
You can rue all you want, but you can't escape me.
十是十四是四十四是十四四十是四十
Meter-maid Mary married manly Matthew Marcus.
是因为我知道这都是演戏
'Cause I know all this is an act.
你需要我 你不是一匹孤狼
You need me. You're not a lone wolf.
孤独者——
Loners are --
哎呀 我输了
Oh, wait, I lost the game.
你在玩文字接龙吗？
You're playing a word game?
原来如此
I see how it is.
看来光动嘴是没用的！
Then we're just going to have to do this by force!
这就是你的方式吗？
Huh? That's how you wanna do things?
这是我们俩之间的事情
This is a matter between you and me.
所以不要把她牵扯进来
So don't lay a hand on her.
那你就可以用机械手抓着她吗？
But it's fine for you to use a big robotic hand?
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
激光束！
Laser beam!
逃避我是没用的！
You can't escape me!
井出！
Ide!
看招！
Take that!
你真是不容易啊！
You've lived a tough life, haven't you?
喂？
Hello?
呃 夫人 我很抱歉 还没做完
Oh, uh, hi, ma'am. I'm sorry. I'm not finished.
我不是说过交给你了吗
I told you I'm counting on you
“时尚蛋奶馅饼女仆宅急送” 服务
for my "Maid Delivers Flan Body a la Mode" service!
-所以你应该… -我现在有急事
So, what I need you to do -- I'm in a middle of something!
你要犯和上次同样的错误吗？！
Are you going to make the same mistake again?!
这样是不会成功的！
There's no light at the end of this tunnel!
-停手吧！-没门！
-Just give it up! -No way, Jose!
已经满垒了
The bases are all loaded!
吃我平飞球！
And it's line drive!
比赛开始！
Play ball!
你不是已经开打了？！
Uh! But haven't you already been playing ball?!
你自己也明白的吧
Come on! You know you're not
这样做是找不到他的！
going to reach him like this, don't you?!
拉哈路！
Raharu!
你一个人是不行的 没有我你是找不到他的
You can't do this alone. You can't reach him without me.
-你心知肚明 -用不着尿裤子
You know this. No need to pee-pee in your panties!
你不可能不明白 因为我们俩本是一体！
The reason you know this is because you and I are one!
个 十 百 千 哈哈
1, 10, 100, 1,000! Haha!
我可是被称为邪恶的火之打者
They call me the Infamous Flaming Slugger!
酷美
Hidomi.
我警告过你不要跟那个女人扯上关系
I warned you not to get involved with that woman.
她只会为了一己之私利用你
She will only use you for her own benefit.
你甚至会因此而死
Worst-case scenario, you could die.
会死？
Could die?
喂 打者 打者 打者!
Hey, batter-batter-batter!
酷美?
Hidomi?
不 酷美！
No, Hidomi!
不可能
No way.
她克服了酶抑制剂？
She overcame the enzyme inhibitor?
抑制？
Inhibition?
咦 那是什么喵？
Huh? What-What-What is that,nya?
你看起来不错
You're looking good.
摸摸不可以喔
No touchy.
酷美！
Hidomi!
发生了什么？
What just happened?
酷美！酷美！
Hidomi! Hidomi!
井出…井出…
Ide...Ide...
别担心
Don't worry.
几个小时内你就会恢复了
You'll be recovered in few hours.
你干得不错 但是
You did a good job. But...
别动！
Hold it right there!
我不管你怎么想
No matter how you slice and dice it,
她是属于我的
we know she's mine.
你看起来糟透了
You look terrible.
作业
Worksheet.
你今天没来学校
'Cause you were absent today.